William Young Correspondence
William Young Correspondence
1882-1919
Young, William, 1847-1920.
33 items.
Papers of the American poet, playwright. Incoming personal letters.
149315
Biographical History
William Young (1847-1920) was an American poet and playwright. Initially a law student, Young turned to drama and writing early in his career, favoring the blank verse technique. His works include "Pendragon," "The Rajah" and "Ganelon." His best-known work is his dramatization of Lew Wallace's "Ben-Hur."
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The William Young Correspondence consists of incoming letters, mostly from fellow members of the Authors Club. Subjects include Young's play "Pendragon," general praise for Young's work, and the social and business activities of the Authors Club members. Correspondents include Samuel Hopkins Adams, Elwyn A. Barron, Clarence Clough Buel, Elizabeth York Case, L.T. Chamberlain, Jeannette L. Gilder, Stuart Oliver Henry, Ellen Mary Hutchinson, Rossiter Johnson, William Denison McCrackan, Morell Mackenzie, Charles Ledyard Norton, Duffield Osborne, Charles George Douglas Roberts, Frank Kimball Scribner, Arthur Stedman, Henry Wilton Thomas, Charles Warner, Charles Henry Webb, and James Carleton Young.
Arrangement of the Collection
The collection is arranged alphabetically by correspondent name.
Subject and Genre Headings
Literature -- American Poetry; Adams, Samuel Hopkins, 1871-1958.; Barron, Elwyn Alfred, 1855-; Buel, Clarence Clough, 1850-1933.; Case, Elizabeth York.; Chamberlain, L. T. (Leander Trowbridge), 1837-1913.; Gilder, Jeannette L. (Jeannette Leonard), 1849-1916.; Henry, Stuart Oliver, b. 1860.; Hutchinson, Ellen Mary.; Johnson, Rossiter, 1840-1931.; McCrackan, William Denison, 1864-1923.; Mackenzie, Morell, 1837-1892.; Norton, Charles Ledyard, 1837-1909.; Osborne, Duffield, 1858-1917.; Roberts, Charles George Douglas, Sir, 1860-1943.; Stedman, Arthur, 1859-1908.; Scribner, Frank Kimball, 1866-1935.; Thomas, Henry Wilton, 1867-; Warner, Charles.; Webb, Charles Henry, 1834-1905.; Young, James Carleton, 1856-1918.; Young, William, 1847-1920.; Authors Club (New York, N.Y.); American literature -- 19th century.; American literature -- 20th century.; American poetry -- 19th century.; American poetry -- 20th century.; Authors, American.; Poets, American.; Correspondence.; Authors.; Poets.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Inventory
- Correspondence
  - Adams, Samuel Hopkins 1918, 4 letters (Box 1)
  - Barron, Elwyn Alfred 1884, 1 letter (Box 1)
  - Buel, Clarence Clough 1896, 1 letter (Box 1)
  - Case, Elizabeth York 1907, 2 letters (Box 1)
  - Chamberlain, Leander Trowbridge 1907, 1 letter (Box 1)
  - Gilder, Jeanette Leonard 1882, 1 letter (Box 1)
  - Henry, Stuart Oliver 1919, 1 letter (Box 1)
  - Hutchinson, Ellen Mary 1882, 1 letter (Box 1)
  - Johnson, Rossiter 1917, 1 letter (Box 1)
  - McCrackan, William Denison 1900, 1 letter (Box 1)
  - MacKenzie, Morell 1883, 2 letters (Box 1)
  - Norton, Charles Ledyard 1907, 1 letter (Box 1)
  - Osborne, Duffield 1904, 2 letters (Box 1)
  - Roberts, Charles George Douglas undated, 1 letter (Box 1)
  - Scribner, Frank Kimball 1898, 1 letter (Box 1)
  - Stedman, Arthur 1888, 1 letter (Box 1)
  - Thomas, Henry Wilton 1907, 1 letter (Box 1)
  - Warner, Charles 1883, 1 letter (Box 1)
  - Webb, Charles Henry undated, 2 letters (Box 1)
  - Young, James Carleton 1904, 1 letter (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous undated, 6 items (Box 1)